Guide to the Edward R. Becker Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Edward R. Becker papers
1943-2006
MS 1929
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
31.86
(74 boxes)
The collection comprises the papers of Judge Edward R. Becker, who served both with the United States District Court of Eastern Pennsylvania and the United States Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit. His papers include correspondence, court memorandums, other court-related documents, speeches, subject files, programs and fliers, and newspaper and journal clippings, mainly related to cases over which he presided. Materials cover from 1943 to 2006, with the bulk from 1972 to 2006.
Becker, Edward R. (Edward Roy), 1933-2006
Scope and Contents
The collection comprises the papers of Judge Edward R. Becker, who served both with the United States District Court of Eastern Pennsylvania and the United States Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit. His papers include correspondence, court memoranda, other court-related documents, speeches, subject files, programs and fliers, and newspaper and journal clippings, mainly related to cases over which he presided. Materials cover from 1943 to 2006, with the bulk from 1972 to 2006.
There are some case materials included in the collection, including papers focusing on Matsushita Electric Industrial Co., Ltd. v. Zenith Radio Corp.. Much of the collection is focused on Becker's other judicial activities though, including his work with asbestos legislation, the Judicial Conference of the United States, and Third Circuit task forces on indigent litigants and the death penalty. Also included are plans for the timing of hiring law clerks in the federal courts, Continuing Legal Education (CLE) courses, especially on representing asylum-seekers in the federal courts, and research on legal concepts such as sentencing guidelines, class action lawsuits, and expert evidence in court hearings. There are also materials related to the Senate confirmation hearings for Justice Samuel A. Alito's nomination to the Supreme Court of the United States. Finally, a small but significant part of the collection includes papers related to Becker's different civic activities, including his work creating a Magna Carta exhibition in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in eight series: I. Correspondence, 1970-2006. II. Judicial activities, 1970-2006. III. Subject files, 1970-2005. IV. Clippings, 1943-2006. V. Professional organizations, 1961-2006. VI. Civic organizations and educational programs, 1979-2006. VII. Personal papers, 1950-2005. VIII. Electronic files, 2003-2004.
Conditions Governing Access
Series VIII, electronic files, is closed until processed. All other materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Flora Lyman Becker, 2013.
Biographical / Historical
Edward Roy Becker was born on May 4, 1933 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. He attended the University of Pennsylvania for his B.A., graduating in 1954. He then received his LL. B. from Yale University in 1957. After graduation, he went into a private law practice, Becker and Becker. He worked in the practice for 13 years. In 1970, President Richard M. Nixon appointed Becker to the United States District Court of Eastern Pennsylvania. In 1982, President Ronald Reagan appointed Becker to the United States Court of Appeals of the Third Circuit. He went on to become the chief judge in 1998 and held that position until May 4, 2003. On that date (his 70th birthday), he was mandatorily assigned senior status. Becker continued to serve on the court until his death from prostate cancer on May 19, 2006. During his time as a judge, he was known to be an expert on antitrust law and use of expert evidence in trials. He also worked on many notable cases, including Matsushita Electric Industrial Co., Ltd. v. Zenith Radio Corp., Artway v. The Attorney General of the State of New Jersey and E.B. v. Verniero,Karcher v. May, United States et al. v. the American Library Association and Amchem Products, Inc. v. Windsor.
Antitrust law; Asbestos -- Law and legislation; Evidence, Expert; Judges; Jurisprudence; Law -- Interpretation and construction; Philadelphia (Pa.); Alito, Samuel A., Jr., 1950-; Becker, Edward R. (Edward Roy), 1933-2006; Specter, Arlen, 1930-2012; United States. Court of Appeals (Third Circuit); United States. District Court (Pennsylvania: Eastern District)
- Correspondence, 1970-2006; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  Series I comprises correspondence Becker received, with occasional copies of letters that Becker sent.
  Business correspondence mainly contains letters of thanks, related information to publications, and letters from lawyers and other judges relating to programs Becker was involved in as well as Becker's opinions and rulings. There are also several folders that are specifically focused on topics, including his work with the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, letters related to general civic causes, and letters sent only to Becker while he served at the Eastern District of Pennsylvania court and the Third Circuit Court of Appeals. For communications between multiple judges at each of these courts, please refer to the memoranda and other court communications folders located within Series II, Judicial activities. For more focused correspondence related to individual topics, individual professional organizations and individual civic causes, please refer to Series III, Series V, and Series VI respectively.
  Personal correspondence includes thank you letters and notes, general letters of news between correspondents, and unofficial communications between different judges and between judges and law clerks. There are also several folders that are focused on specific topics, including congratulatory notes related to specific awards and letters to businesses.
  - Chronological business
    - 1972-1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1999, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 2003-2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Alphabetical business
    - Administrative Office of the United States Court, 1987-2006 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Alito, Samuel A., 1992-2006 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Breyer, Stephen, 1985-2005, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Civic causes, 2002-2006 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - District Court, Eastern District of Pennsylvania, 1971-1980 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - O'Connor, Sandra Day, 1992-2006, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Scalia, Antonin, 1991-2002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Souter, David H., 1996-2005 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Stevens, John Paul, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Third Circuit Court of Appeals, 1983-2006, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Thomas, Clarence, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Chronological personal
    - 1971-1980 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 1981-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1990-1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1995 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 1996 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - 1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - 1999 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 2001 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 2002 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - 2004 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - 2005 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - 2006 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Undated (Box 5, Folder 4-6)
    - Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Alphabetical personal
    - Amtrak- cellphones, 2000-2002 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Becker stepping down as chief judge of the Third Circuit, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Congratulatory notes-William J. Brennan, Jr. Distinguished Jurist Award, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Congratulatory notes- Edward J. Devitt Distinguished Service to Justice Award, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 5-7)
    - Congratulatory notes on his appointment to the Eastern District of Pennsylvania Court, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
    - Congratulatory notes on his appointment to the Third Circuit Court of Appeals, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
    - Congratulatory notes on his appointment to the Third Circuit Court of Appeals, 1982 (Box 7a, Folder 1)
    - Ginsburg, Ruth Bader, 1993-1999 (Box 7a, Folder 2)
- Judicial activities, 1970-2006; Series II
  Series II contains materials from Becker's positions at the Eastern District of Pennsylvania Court and the Third Circuit Court of Appeals. Contents include materials related to his appointment to the Eastern District of Pennsylvania and the Third Circuit courts, case materials, court memoranda and other communications, legal opinions, and specific projects and events Becker was involved in. Series II also contains files pertaining to other activities not directly related to his work with those courts, including his work on asbestos litigation and a law clerk hiring plan. There are also materials related to an investigation by the Board of Censors of allegations by Bruce W. Praeger and Gerald M. Bonino against A. Charles Peruto involving Becker and others for misconduct. Finally, there is a section of photographs that depict court functions and include official court portraits, many of which are undated.
  - Eastern District of Pennsylvania Court
    - Acknowledgment letters related to swearing-in ceremony, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Appointment to the court: biographical background, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
    - Board of Censors investigation, 1979, undated (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
    - Board of Censors investigation, 1979, undated (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - General case materials, 1975, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Humor awards, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Humor awards, 1979-1980 (Box 56)
    - Materials related to Matsushita v. Zenith case, 1980-1989 (Box 9, Folder 6-8)
    - Memoranda and other court communications, 1975-1980 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Notes and other materials, 1978-1981 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Notes and other materials, 1978-1981 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Opinions, reports and transcripts, 1974-1980 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Judge Joseph Lord retirement party, Circa 1982; 1 (Box 58)
  - Third Circuit Court of Appeals
    - General, 1982-2003 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
    - General memorabilia, 1980 (Box 56)
    - General memorabilia, Undated (Box 57)
    - First application for nomination, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Second application for nomination, 1978-1981 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Appointment and confirmation to the Third Circuit, 1979-1982 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Appointment and confirmation to the Third Circuit, 1979-1982 (Box 11, Folder 1-3)
    - Appointment and induction to the Third Circuit, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Case materials
      - Docket file, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Draft opinions, 1988-2005 (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
      - Motions, orders, and petitions, 1991-2002 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Opinions to be filed and submitted, 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Freethought Society v. County of Chester, 2003; 1 (Box 59)
      - Freethought Society v. County of Chester, 2003; 1 (Box 60)
      - Georgine v. Amchem Products, Circa 1994; 1 (Box 61)
      - Georgine v. Amchem Products, Circa 1994; 1 (Box 62)
      - Georgine v. Amchem Products, Circa 1994; 1 (Box 63)
      - Georgine v. Amchem Products, Circa 1994; 1 (Box 64)
      - Supreme Court materials related to Third Circuit cases appealed, 1995-1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Supreme Court petitions for a Writ of Certiorari, 1985-1998 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Ceremonies and dedications
      - Celebratory resolutions and proclamations, 1990-2003 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Lobby dedication, 1997-2001 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Programs and fliers, 1982-2005 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Programs and fliers, 1982-2005 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Programs from party sing-a-longs, 1995-2003 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Remarks and speeches, 1996-2001 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Consolidation of the clerk's office and the staff attorney's office, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Coordinating group of financial disclosure legislation, 2000-2001 (Box 13, Folder 5-7)
    - Coordinating group of financial disclosure legislation, 2000-2001 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Design of the James A. Byrne Court House lobby, 1999-2000 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Future Agenda of the Court of Appeals, Third Circuit, 1991-1997 (Box 14, Folder 2-3)
    - Judicial outreach in schools, 1987-2000 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Legal opinions
      - Circuit and district courts, 1984-2004 (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
      - Circuit and district courts, 1984-2004 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Supreme Court of the United States, 1990-2004 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Third Circuit, 1986-2005 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - List of accomplishments, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Memoranda and other court communications
      - 1982-1989 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - 1990-1993 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - 1996-1999 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - 2001-2003 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - 2004-2005 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Naming of the Allentown courthouse, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Newark/Pittsburgh sittings, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Speeches- Third Circuit Accomplishments, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Task Force for Furnishing Counsel for Indigent Litigants, 1997-2000 (Box 16, Folder 8-10)
    - Task Force for Furnishing Counsel for Indigent Litigants, 1997-2000 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Task Force for Furnishing Counsel to Indigent Litigants- July 9, 1998 Task Force Meeting (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Task Force for Furnishing Counsel for Indigent Litigants- recording of meeting, 1998 March 5; 1 (Box 65)
    - Task Force for Furnishing Counsel for Indigent Litigants- recording of meeting, 1998 March 5; 1 (Box 66)
    - Task Force on the Death Penalty, 1998-2003 (Box 17, Folder 3-6)
    - Task Force on the Death Penalty, 1998-2003 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - Other judicial activities
    - Asbestos legislation
      - 1998-2003 (Box 18, Folder 3-5)
      - 2003 (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
      - 2003 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
      - 2003-2004 (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
      - 2004 April (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - 2004 May (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - 2004 April-August (Box 19, Folder 7-8)
      - 2004 April-August (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - 2004 August (Box 20, Folder 2-4)
      - 1995-2005 (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - 2004-2005 (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Biographies and backgrounds, 1989-2003 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Contact lists, Undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Drafts and drafting notes of the Fairness in Asbestos Injury Resolution Act (FAIR Act), 2005-2006 (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Drafts and drafting notes of the Fairness in Asbestos Injury Resolution Act (FAIR Act), 2005-2006 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Handwritten notes, Circa 2005 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Proposed claim system, 2003 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Testimony and notes related to the Fairness in Asbestos Injury Resolution Act (FAIR Act), Undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Transcript of proceedings before the United States Senate Committee of the Judiciary (Fairness in Asbestos Injury Resolution Act), 2003 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Asylum-Seekers
      - "Representing Asylum-Seekers in the Circuit Courts" continuing legal education (CLE) course, 2004-2005 (Box 21, Folder 6-9)
      - "Representing Asylum-Seekers in the Circuit Courts" continuing legal education (CLE) course, 2004-2005 (Box 22, Folder 1-6)
      - "Representing Asylum-Seekers in the Circuit Courts" continuing legal education (CLE) course, 2004-2005 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Asylum Seekers: Video Introduction by Sandra Day O'Connor, 2005 September 28; 1 (Box 67)
    - Habeas Corpus bill, 2005 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Judicial Conference of the United States
      - Advisory committee on alternatives to imprisonment, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Automation of probation system/mandatory minimums, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Drug aftercare testimony, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Enhanced supervision seminar, probation testimony center, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Guideline recommendation material for sentencing guidelines, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Materials related to Brookings Institute speech on drug policy, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Materials related to mandatory minimum sentencing and "Federal Day", 1990 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - Meeting with Boyden Gray regarding mandatory minimums, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - Notes related to sentencing guidelines, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - Probation office, District of New Jersey report for year ending June 30, 1989, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - Proposed long-range plan for the federal courts, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Role of probation officer training, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Sentencing guidelines training, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Sentencing guidelines training seminar, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Statement regarding proposed amendments to sentencing guidelines, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Testimony before the sentencing commission
        - 1986 (Box 24, Folder 5)
        - 1988 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Testimony before subcommittee on crime, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Testimony before subcommittee on criminal justice, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Testimony on drug testing, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Testimony on pretrial detention, 1989-1990 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Warden's Conference, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Law clerk hiring timing plans
      - 1979-1987 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - 1988 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - 1988-1993 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - 1988-1998 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - 1990 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - 1991-1992 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - 1993 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - 1994 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - 1994-1995 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - 1994-1998 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Article for the Yale Law Journal, 1986-1995 (Box 26, Folder 4-6)
      - Law clerk hiring proposals, 2002 (Box 26, Folder 7-8)
      - Law clerk hiring proposals, 2002 (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
      - Law clerk hiring proposals, 2002-2003 (Box 27, Folder 4-5)
      - Proposal to reform the law clerk hiring process, 1999-2002 (Box 27, Folder 6-7)
      - Proposal to reform the law clerk hiring process, 1999-2002 (Box 27a, Folder 1)
      - Questionnaire returns used for the Yale Law School Journal article, 1993 (Box 27a, Folder 2)
      - Reactions to the proposed law clerk hiring plan, 2003 (Box 27a, Folder 3)
  - Photographs
    - Court events, 1998 (Box 27a, Folder 4)
    - Court events, Undated (Box 27a, Folder 5-6)
    - Full court portraits, Undated (Box 27a, Folder 7)
    - Full court portraits, Undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Official portraits of Edward R. Becker, Undated (Box 27a, Folder 8)
- Subject files, 1970-2005; Series III
  Series III contains materials on topics that were of interest to Becker, much of it for research on cases, law journal articles, or speeches. Materials include clippings, internal court documents, correspondence, and interviews with Becker. Some of these subjects are directly related to cases and causes in which Becker was involved; others are more tangentially of interest.
  - General, 1970-1989 (Box 28, Folder 1-2)
  - Adams, Arlin, 1967-2005 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Alito confirmation hearings
    - 2005 (Box 28, Folder 4-7)
    - 2005 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - 2005-2006 (Box 29, Folder 2-3)
    - 2006 (Box 29, Folder 4-5)
    - "The Alito Opinions" Report, 2005 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Analysis of legal opinions- "Cases in which there is direct disagreement: outcome different", Circa 2005 (Box 29, Folder 7-9)
    - Analysis of legal opinions- "Cases in which there is direct disagreement: outcome different", Circa 2005 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Analysis of legal opinions- "Cases in which either Becker or Alito conc. or dis. from majority", Circa 2005 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Alternative structures of the Court of Appeals
    - 1995-2000 (Box 30, Folder 3-7)
    - Ninth Circuit split, 1998-2005 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Cameras in courtroom
    - General
      - 1994-1999, undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - 2000, undated (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - 2001, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - 2002, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - 2003-2004, undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - "Justice Talking", 2004, undated (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Newshour with Jim Lehrer, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Newshour with Jim Lehrer- video recording, 2000 November 30; 1 (Box 68)
    - Newsmakers: Edward R. Becker- video recording, 2002 July 19; 1 (Box 69)
    - Testimony before Senate subcommittee on Senate bill S. 721 background material, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Testimony before Senate subcommittee on Senate bill S. 721 briefing notebook, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 10-11)
    - Today Show- video recording, 2000 November 27; 1 (Box 70)
    - United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, 2005 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Certifications of questions of law, 1996-1998 (Box 32, Folder 1-4)
  - Class action lawsuits, 1995-2006 (Box 32, Folder 5-6)
  - Class action lawsuits, 1995-2006 (Box 33, Folder 1-4)
  - Daubert standard of evidence, 1995-2005 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Daubert standard of evidence, 1995-2005 (Box 34, Folder 1-2)
  - Equalization of judges' salaries, 2005 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Footnotes- materials related to article, 1990-1996 (Box 34, Folder 4-5)
  - Footnotes- materials related to article, 1990-1996 (Box 35, Folder 1-3)
  - General Services Administration- rent, 2005 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Gillespie, Patrick, 1982-2005 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Immigration: "Immigration law in the Ninth Circuit", 2005 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Racism in the judicial system, 1970, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Sentencing guidelines
    - 1989-1991 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Sentencing guidelines article, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - Smith, D. Brooks, 2000-2002 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Speaking engagements, 1972-1985 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Speeches/speech materials
    - General, 1971-2003 (Box 36, Folder 5-6)
    - Commencements, 1931-2003 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Indiana University Law School commencement, 1993 May 8 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Sentencing guidelines, 1991-1993 (Box 37, Folder 3-5)
  - Virgin Islands Article III court, 1997-2004 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Virgin Islands assignment to the Third Circuit, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 7)
- Clippings, 1943-2005; Series IV
  Series IV contains newspaper clippings, magazine clippings, printouts from websites, and law journals. A majority of the clippings concern Becker's cases or his areas of judicial interest. There are also several folders with articles about friends and colleagues of Becker, including obituaries and law journal tributes.
  - General cases Becker presided over, 1975-2004 (Box 38, Folder 1-3)
  - General- Judicial activities, 1977-2005 (Box 38, Folder 4-6)
  - General- Law journal articles, 1943-2005 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - General- Law journal articles, 1943-2005 (Box 39, Folder 1-3)
  - General- personal, 1977-2005 (Box 39, Folder 4-6)
  - Alito, Samuel A., 2005-2006 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Antitrust- Zenith case, 1980-1995 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Asbestos legislation, 2003-2005 (Box 40, Folder 3-4)
  - Asbestos litigation, 1996-2004 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Becker, Edward R., 1980-2005 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Casino unions, 1983-1984 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Copyright/intellectual property law, 1986-1997 (Box 40, Folder 8-9)
  - Death notices, obituaries, and tributes, 1968-2004 (Box 41, Folder 1)